Walter and Naomi Rosenblum Collection of Photography and Photographic History MSS.556
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Naomi Rosenblum's Research Materials, Correspondence, Subject Files, and Lectures, 1860-2018 (inclusive), 1963-2014 (bulk); 21.38 Linear Feet in 49 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 4 oversized flat boxes, and 1 flat file folder
  - Thomas Gunther, 1984-1989, 1991, 1995-1996 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Hine Exhibit-Italy, 2005, 2007, 2010-2015 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Whitney Museum Project, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - AWHOP - Polish Edition, 2005 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Empire State, 1989-1990 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Deerfield Visit/Engelland/April, 2001 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Willie Williams/Haverford, 1999, 2000, 2006 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Haiti Orphan Project, 2007 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Oxford U Press/Dr. Robin Lenman, 2000, 2002 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Whitney/AM Century Show, 1996, 2001 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Albany Inst/Miles/Lindley Project, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Grant to Aperture from V. Stevens Trust Fund, 2007-2009 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Photog Lectures/Manhattanville College, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Grad Center/CUNY, 1999-2000 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Otterbein, 2001-2002 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Carriere/Gaspe, 2010 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Getty/Strand, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Twin Lenses, 2008 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Twin Lenses Movie Poster (consultant - Naomi Rosenblum), 2008 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Soc. Photo Ed, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Toronto, 1987, 2006 (Box 41, Folder 8-9)
  - Spanish Conf, 2009-2010 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Swank, Bossen (Pittsburgh), 2004 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Brazil/NaFoto, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Same Ideas on the Sources of the Bayeux Tapestry (Naomi Rosenblum), 1970 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Corr Re: Alinari, 1982, 1996, 1998, 2002-2003 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Sesquicentennial Stuff (UPenn), 1989-1990 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - SF MoMA, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Sesquic/Photo, 1988-1989 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - NR Notebooks, undated (Box 42, Folder 3-8)
  - St. T. Aquinas Talk Women, 2009 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Fred Ritchin, 2006-2007 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Chernobyl Project, 2004-2006 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Photo Series/Reece/Hamilton, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia (Stand in a Different Place), 1986 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Penn State Press, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Padua, 2004 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Oxford Encyc, Robin Lenman, Joanna Harris, 2005 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Art Journal, article on Georgia O'Keeffe, 1992 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Norton/Mairs/Compassion etc, 2004 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Marlborough School/Nov 30, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Mom-Seguna-Feira, 1994,1998 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Corr Re: Photog, 1995, 2005-2006 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Mexican Photo Series, 1986-1989 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Mignon, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Lerner Memorial, 2008 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Loyola/Laughlin, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - "On Photography" (Teju Cole), 2017 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Kornblum - "Art of Photography?", 1995 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - KCTA - Photog/TV Series, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - J. Paul Getty - Symposium, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Haverford/Spe, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Lehman College, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - ICP/Dmitri, 1955, 1957, 1959-1961, 1964, 1967-1968, 1981, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Fugenzi, 2009 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 2005-2006, 2008, 2010, 2016 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Foto Art Festival/Program Show & Talk, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Donation WWII Museum, 2018 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Mauro Minotto, Text & Pix, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - The New Yorker Magazine - Paul Strand Article, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Naomi Rosenblum - College Papers, 1971-1974 (Box 44, Folder 8-9)
  - Frye/Seattle, 2002-2003 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Encyclopedia of 19th C Photography/Roberts/Braun, 2001 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Blacks in Photos, 1995 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Allen Sisters/Flynt Memorial Hall Museum, 2000-2001 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - CRAF/Frivli Proposal, 2002 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Ency of NY, 2007 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Photographies, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Lehman/Hind/Strand, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Amon Carter, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Berkshire MU, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - David Freese (Phila), 2011 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Aniello Barone, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Soc/Pho/Abbeville Lyon, 2000-2001 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - The Georgia Committee of the National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Lumiere & High Mu Atlanta, 2008 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - A. Barone, 2007 (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Barone/Fugenzi
    - Digital Files, FA_MSS_556_ER_7
    - Paper Files, 2007; cuid36373 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - U of CA/Chicago, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Italy, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Casa Sola Photo/Permission for 1985 postcard Reproduction, 1985-1988 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Pacific Pictures/Lange, 1989-1992, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Publicity/General NR, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Poland Re: Publication of AWHOP, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - CCP (Center for Creative Photography), 1976-1980, 1983, 1985-1990, 1994, 2002, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Americana Iralian Show/Liva, 2008 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Aperture/Latin AM, 1987, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Dituri/Italy, 2007-2010 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - CIOL, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Umicini, 2002 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Pietropaolo, Vincenzo, 2008, 2010 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica Kozitka, 2001, 2003 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - NR Misc Notes, undated (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Boston, 2008 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - ICP Gift/Weegee, 2011 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Naomi Rosenblum - Diary at Orgeval (Strand), undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Mayer & Pierson, La Photographie Consideree comme art et Comme L'Industrie Paris, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Research Materials - History of Photography, undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Bill Clinton to Naomi Rosenblum, 2010 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Photographic Advertising from A-to-Z: From Kodak to Leica (Vol 1 & 2) (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Kean Forum (James Jandrowitz/Naomi Rosenblum), 1997 (Box 65, Vhs 556_0002)
  - Paul Strand: The Early Years, 1910-1932 (Naomi Rosenblum's PhD Dissertation), 1978 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Paul Strand Folder, undated (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Workers - Sebastiao Salgado (Aperture), 1993 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Lewis Hine Article by Naomi Rosenblum, undated (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Excellence in Photographic Writing Award to Naomi Rosenblum, 1989 (Box 92)
  - In Mine and Mill (Earl Dotter), 1979 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Life of the Appalachian Coal Miner (Builder Levy - photographers), 1976 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - A History of Photography of California Collections Flyer, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - "Hine: I wanted to show the things that had to be corrected" 1874-1940 (Arts Council of Great Britain), undated (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Lewis Hine Day - State of NY Proclamation, 1984 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - The Port Washington Public Library Newspaper (article about Naomi Rosenblum), 1992 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Picture (Magazine), 1980 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Workers (Louis Stettner), 1974 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Hine/Misc Activities, circa 1920s and 1930s (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Orgeval - A Remembrance of Paul Strand by Naomi Rosenblum, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - American Photography Magazine, undated (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Focus on the Soul: The Photographs of Lottie Jacobi, undated; FA_MSS_556_ER_1
  - America and Lewis Hine: A Film by Nina Rosenblum (poster), 1984 (Box 93, Folder 12, Box Shared Fales 073, Folder 8)
  - Lewis Hine Diploma, 1905 (Box Shared Fales 073, Folder 6)
  - "Light Years" - Albin O. Kuhn Library & Gallery Poster (feat. Lewis Hine), 1989 (Flat-file-folder 7)
  - Brooklyn Museum Lewis Hine Timeline Poster, 1977 (Flat-file-folder 7)
  - Xeroxes Women's Work, undated (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Collection of British Authors Vol 515: Transformation or the Romance of Monte Beni by Nathaniel Hawthorne (Volumes 1 & 2), 1860 (Box 95, Item 1-4)
  - History of Free St. Peter's Church, Glasgow, 1886 (Box 96, Item 8)
  - Photographic Process Examples - Photograph Albums, undated (Box 96, Item 1-7)
  - Photographic Process Examples - Prints, circa 1900-2018 (Box 97, Box 98, Box 99, Box 100, Box 101, Box 102, Box 103, Box 104, Box 105, Folder 8-12, Box Shared Fales 073, Folder 10-11)
  - Photographic Process Examples - Glass Plate Negative, undated (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Photographic Process Examples - Daguerrotype, undated (Box 109, Box 110)
  - Photographic Process Examples - Ambrotypes, undated (Box 108)
  - Photographic Process Examples - Tintypes, undated (Box 107, Box 108, Box 111)
  - Photographic Process Examples - Photograph Buttons and other formats, undated (Box 111)
- Series II: Walter Rosenblum, 1938-2018; 23.74 Linear Feet in 27 manuscript boxes, 2 half manuscript box, 2 media boxes, 4 flat boxes, 6 oversized flat boxes, and 7 flat file folder
  Series II contains various materials and subjects related to Walter Rosenblum including photographs, scrapbooks, articles about Walter's career, exhibition materials, research notes, and lecture notes. The series also include audiovisual and born-digital items containing interviews with Walter about his work and career, as well as interviews with colleagues like Paul Strand.
  Note: Box 89 contains legal documents that are restricted.
  The materials in both the larger series and sub-series have been arranged thematically.
  - Bio Beginning by Michael Torosian, 1999 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Autobio-1 (one article), undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Autobiography 2, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Autobio 3 (various), undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Various plus "Travel Journal", 1981-1983, 1999, 2001 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - WR - Education, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Bios + Obituary, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Memoir of WR begun by James McCarthy, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Shelley Rice - Walter Rosenblum: Paying Homage Through Photo, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Proposed Book - Writings About WR's Photos, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - "Walter Rosenblum - Lewis Hine, Paul Strand, and the Photo League", undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - New York City Venezi Magazine (Article about WR), 2004 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Italian Articles about Walter Rosenblum, 2005 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Cover of James T. Farrell's Studs Lonigan (uses WR photograph), undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Fotografie Magazine, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Inside: Rivista di Cultura Contemporanea (Contemporary Culture Magazine), 2007 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Camera Magazine, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - The Reminiscnes of Walter Rosenblum (Oral History Research Office - Columbia University), 1980 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of WR during WWII (US Army Signal Corps Photographer), 1944 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Museum - WR List, 2013 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Invitational Teaching Conference at the George Eastman House, 1962 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Ronda Magazine, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - South Africa-South Bronx (Peter Magubane, Walter Rosenblum), 1981 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Walter Rosenblum Interview Transcript, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - D-Day Museum Opening Photographs, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Black and White Photographs of Walter Rosenblum, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Newman & Ishimoto - Reunion in Chicago: Photographs from 1949-52, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Invitational Exhibition 10/American Photographers 10, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - The Washington Post, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Walter Rosenblum Calendar, 2007 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - "The Camera and Art" (H. William Collins, EE '52), 1952 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - "The Gaspe Revisted: A Documentary Vacation" in Modern Photography Magazine (WR photos used), 1954 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Newsclippings Using WR Photographs, undated (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - "The Art of Photography" Panel Discussion College Art Association, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - "Shooting War" (DGA Magazine), 2000 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Black and White Photos of WR Exhibition, undated (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Walter Rosenblum & WWII, 1945, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Articles about Walter Rosenblum, undated (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - WR - Russia, 2012 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - China/Hine/China, 1980 (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - WR - Hine Letter of Recommendation for Walter, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - WR - Photo of Reinhardt, 2017; cuid36374 (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - WR/Press Pack, 1976-1977, 1986, 1997-1998 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - WR - Wins $30 Prize, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - WR Film, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - WR Motta Captions/Pics, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Students of WR, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Walter Rosenblum (1919-2006), undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Essay about Walter Rosenblum (author unknown), undated (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Post-War Mentions of WR War Photography & Articles About, 1976, 1970, 1975, 1993-1994, 2001, 2005 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Post WWII Misc, 1946, 1991-1992, 1994, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Italy: Seravezza Clippings, 2005 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - WR Scrapbook #1, 1939-1966 (Box 51)
  - WR Scrapbook #2, 1949, 1952, 1955, 1962-1967 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - WR Scrapbook #3, 1968-1976 (Box 50, Folder 11, Box 62, Folder 5)
  - WR Scrapbook #4, 1970-1976 (Box 51)
  - WR Scrapbook #5, 1977-1979 (Box 50, Folder 12-13)
  - WR Scrapbook #6, 1980-1982 (Box 52)
  - WR Scrapbook #7, 1983-1986 (Box 53)
  - WR Scrapbook #8, 1987-1989 (Box 54)
  - WR Scrapbook #9, 1990-1992 (Box 55)
  - WR Scrapbook #10, 1993-1994 (Box 56)
  - WR Scrapbook #11, 1995-1996 (Box 57)
  - WR Scrapbook #12, 1997 (Box 58, Folder 1-2)
  - WR Scrapbook #13, 1998 (Box 58, Folder 3-5)
  - WR Scrapbook #14, Jan-Jun 1999 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
  - WR Scrapbook #15, Jul-Dec 1999 (Box 59, Folder 3-4)
  - WR Scrapbook #16, 2000-2001 (Box 60, Folder 3-4)
  - WR Scrapbook #17, 2001-2002 (Box 59, Folder 5, Box 61, Folder 1)
  - WR Scrapbook #18, 2002-2003 (Box 61, Folder 2-3)
  - WR Scrapbook #19, 2003-2004 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - WR Scrapbook #20 & #21, 2004 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - WR Scrapbook #22, 2005 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - WR Scrapbook #23, 2005-2006 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - WR Scrapbook #24, 2006 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - WR Scrapbook #25, 2007-2010 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Excerpt from Ovo Magazine, 1961 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Various Writings about Rosenblum, undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - WR: Bio info & a few interviews, etc…, undated (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - WR Student Letters, undated (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Faber Spanish Project/WR Refugee Exhibit, 2008 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Blair/U. Mich/Girl on Swing/WR, 2010 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Serravezza, 2005 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Walter Rosenblum Exhibition Promotional Material & Articles, 1990-1992 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Camera & Darkroom: The Magazine for Creative Photographers (Article about WR), 1991 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence (Re: publication of WR book, including personal letters & comments about world situation), 1987-1990 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Simon Wiesenthal Center Honors the Witnesses to the Truth, Eigth Annual Eastern Regional Dinner, 1985 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Book Introduction - Walter Rosenblum, photographer, 1990 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Aperture: 40 Yrs, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Let Truth Be the Prejudice: Photographs of W. Eugene Smith, undated (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Articles about Naomi & Walter Rosenblum, 1996-1998 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Vertigo (Louise DeSalvo) Book Cover, 1997 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - A Voice for Children…A Decade of Achievement, 1998 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - 望星 (Nozomi) - Japanese Magazine, 1997 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - WR Film - D-Day Museum, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Seminici Magazine (article about WR), 1999 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Photo Edizione Italiana Magazine (Article about WR), 1999 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Admira-Chicca Vigano (Milano), 2007 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Walter Rosenblum Calendar, 2007 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Trace Magazine (article about WR), 2007 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Photography Magazines with Articles about WR, 1981, 2010, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Heroes Among Us - American Institute of Graphic Arts New Orleans Chapter Calendar, 1999 (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - International Articles about Walter Rosenblum, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Exhibit in Moscow, 2009-2010 (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - Fernando and Mignon to WR, 2003 (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - A WNET montage; IMPORTANCE OF PHOTOGRAPH X, undated (Box 65, Vhs 556_0001)
  - International Center of Photography (14th Annual Infinity Awards), 1998 (Box 65, Vhs 556_0003)
  - Video Presentacion PHotoEspana 99, 1999 (Box 65, Vhs 556_0005)
  - Seminario Internacional de Fotografia, 1994 (Box 65, Vhs 556_0006)
  - Untitled VHS Tape, undated (Box 65, Vhs 556_0007)
  - Brooklyn College Arts Department, undated (Box 65, Vhs 556_0008)
  - Walter et Naomi Rosenblum a L'Ecole Nationale de la Photographie, undated (Box 65, Vhs 556_0009)
  - Walter Rosenblum Paul Strand Interviews, 1971 (Box 66, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0010-556_0017)
  - Untitled Audio Reel, undated (Box 66, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0018)
  - Peter Magubane #2 of 4 (Daedalus, Deb's TLS Out), 1984 (Box 66, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0020)
  - Peter Magubane #3 of 4 (Daedalus, Deb's TLS Out), 1984 (Box 67, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0027)
  - Walter at Hirsch Horn A. Tape No. 5, 1995 (Box 66, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0021)
  - Paul Strand (copy of Los Stettmers Tape), undated (Box 66, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0022)
  - Strand Memorial, undated (Box 66, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0023)
  - Bonbat A. Tape No. 4, 1973 (Box 67, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0024)
  - Strand A. Tape No. 8/Eye On Art - Paul Strand, 1972 (Box 67, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0025)
  - Doisneau A. Tape No. 6, undated (Box 67, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0026)
  - Strand Archive, undated (Box 67, Quarter inch audio reel 556_0028)
  - WWII - Int. w. Walter Rosenblum, 1998 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0030)
  - W.R. Interview 8, undated (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0031)
  - Walter Rosenblum - Lecture Mead Art Museum, 1995 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0032)
  - Walter & Michael (Tape 1), 1996 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0033)
  - Walter & Michael (Tape 2), 1996 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0034)
  - Walter Rosenblum (& Lili Corbus Bezner) (Tape 1), 1992 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0036)
  - Walter Rosenblum (& Lili Corbus Bezner) (Tape 2), 1992 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0035)
  - Walter Rosenblum interviewed by Leonard LoPate on WNYC Radio, 1991 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0037)
  - Walter Rosenblum (Follow Your Star, Documentary vs. Social Photography), 1996 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0038)
  - Walter Rosenblum - Penn State University, 1995 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0039)
  - W.R. Interview 8, undated (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0040)
  - Michael Hoffman Walter Rosenblum, 1994 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0041)
  - Walter Rosenblum - World War II Project, 1996 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0042)
  - Interview W.R., 1991 (Box 68, Audiocassette 556_0043)
  - WBAI Vet Day Special (cont'd) Col Bates & Gates, 1992 (Box 69, Audiocassette 556_0044-556_0045)
  - Walter Rosenblum, 1996 (Box 69, Audiocassette 556_0046)
  - Walter Rosenblum on Gilles Peress/On Teaching, 1996 (Box 69, Audiocassette 556_0047)
  - NY & Company w/ Leonard Lopate - Rosenblum, 1991 (Box 69, Audiocassette 556_0048)
  - Walter/Lower East Side (Nina Rosenblum), 1996 (Box 69, Audiocassette 556_0049)
  - Walter Rosenblum/Interview with Ken Light, undated (Box 69, Audiocassette 556_0050)
  - W.R./Soc. For Photographic Education, 1995 (Box 69, Audiocassette 556_0051)
  - Walter's Book Party #2, 1991 (Box 69, Hi8 556_0052)
  - Untitled 8 mm Video Cassette, undated (Box 69, Hi8 556_0053)
  - Walter Lower East Side, 1996 (Box 69, Dat 556_0054)
  - WR, PHE Show Opening, 2005 (Box 69, Minidv 556_0055)
  - "Walter" Pitt St. Shoot 1, 1996 (Box 69, Minidv 556_0056)
  - Student Photographs Collected by Walter Rosenblum, undated (Box 105, Folder 1-7, Box 106)
  - (Unframed) Student Photographs collected by Walter Rosenblum, undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Essay about Walter and Naomi Rosenblum (in Italian), undated (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Annie - Japanese Musical Souvenir Program (includes article featuring WR's work), 1986 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - International Award of Photography for WR and NR, 2004 (Box 91)
  - Comune di Seravezza award for WR, 2005 (Box 91)
  - Circolo Fotografico L'Altissimo award for WR, 2003 (Box 90)
  - Newspaper Clippings about Walter Rosenblum, 1983, 1993 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Carole Thompson - China Photo Press, 2006 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Walter Rosenblum: In Search of Pitt Street Poster (Nina Rosenblum), 1999 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Lieux et Visages - Faces and Places, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Calle Mayor - Fotografia urbana en America (features WR photography), 2005 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - The Liberators: The Simon Wiesenthal Center Honors the American Soliders Who Liberated European Jewry (WR Honored), 1985 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - "The Great Oshkosh Woodworkers Strike of 1898" in Green Mountain Quarterly (related to WR and Lewis Hine), 1985 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Silver Image Gallery, 1991-1994 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - D-Day Landing Photograph by WR, undated (Box Shared Fales 073, Folder 7)
  - Seravezza Fotografia 2005 1a Parte, FA_MSS_556_ER_2
  - Seravezza Fotografia 2005 2a Parte, FA_MSS_556_ER_5
  - WR Bio.3 Bio.4, undated; FA_MSS_556_ER_4
  - Yale at Norfolk Art Division Poster (feat. WR), 1972, 1974 (Flat-file-folder 7)
  - Portraits of Walter Rosenblum, undated
  - Sub-series II.A: Master Prints, 1938-1980; 2 Linear Feet in 2 flat boxes
    Sub-series II.A contains approximately 116 black and white master photographic prints produced by Walter Rosenblum illustrating his time in France during WWII, his Haiti series, South Bronx series, Pitt Street series, Gaspe series, Europe 1973 series, and East Harlem series.
    The arrangement of the photographs in this sub-series is based upon the themes of Walter Rosenblum's photograph projects; photographs belonging to the same series have been grouped together.
    - Boy with Straw Hat - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Landscape - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Landscape with Two Branches - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Clearing Fields - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Boy in White Shawl - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Funeral Altar - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Flirtation - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Woman in Azacr(?) Robe (#105) - Haiti, 1957-1958 (Box 71)
    - Market Place (#104) - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Baron Samedi (#102) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Tombstone (#103) - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Woman on Boat in Bay (#101) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Peristyle Cooking (#107) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Woman Selling at Rest Stop (#106) - Petionville, Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Bringing Produce from Mountain to Market in Petionville (#100) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Prayer (#99) - Saut-D'Eau, Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Woman Leaning on Pole (#98) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Tourist with Camera (#97) - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Rest Stop (#96) - Petionville, Haiti, 1957-1958 (Box 71)
    - Child Learning on Chair (#95) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Children Playing (#94) - Gonaives, Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Boy Pulling Toy Wagon (#93) - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 71)
    - Beggars (#92) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Blind Woman (#91) - Haiti, 1958 (Box 70)
    - Funeral Group (#90) - Petionville, Haiti, 1958 (Box 70)
    - Ici Marie Michel (#89) - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 70)
    - Two Boys and Tombstone (#87) - Petionville, Haiti, 1958 (Box 71)
    - Peristyle Cooking (#86) - Haiti, 1958-1959 (Box 70)